Hello friends of Marvelous Designer, welcome to this tutorial
First we need to import a virtual model, here we import Feifei
Then click on Modular Configurator to switch to the module configurator
Open the Women folder and open the Shirts folder
Double click on the short sleeve shirt icon, there will be modules in various parts at the bottom
Double-click on the modules to import them
In the Modular Configurator, you can import modules to create all kinds of costumes
If you want to change the model of a module, you only need to double-click on another model to replace it
Please follow the video description for more information
In the Modular Configurator, select these modules
Switch the module window to the Library window and open the Avata folder
Since all the preview modules are done in a vertical position, we need to change the virtual model position to match them
Re-activate the costume file, we will change the position
Open the Female V2 folder under the Pose folder
Download the vertical position file and select default settings
Since we have re-activated the costume, when we change the position
The costume will not participate in the simulation together
After the action is changed, we can activate the shirt
Open the simulation and put the shirt on the virtual model
To make it easier to edit the costume, we need to re-apply the symmetrical edit relationship to the version
Before that, we need to remove the module relationship
Select the module frame with the adjustment version tool, then press the Delete button to remove the module relationship
Then select all the panels, press the Right button to select the panel
In the pop-up menu, select the
Unite
So that the panels are returned to the time when there is no symmetrical relationship
Use the internal multidirectional line tool to create the back and middle lines of the body panels
To cut the panels in half
Please use these straight lines to create the internal lines
In the pop-up menu, select the cut line
In the pop-up menu, select the cut seam option
After that, select all panels other than the collar
In the pop-up menu, select the symmetrical panel, panel and seam function at the bottom of the link panel option
Now the panel line is displayed as dark blue, and the symmetry relationship has been set
Switch to the edit seam tool, you will see that the seam line is also automatically symmetrical
Then select the cut seam option
Then select the seam line between the top and bottom of the back and bottom
In the right-click menu, select merge, merge the panels
Then switch to the edit panel tool
Select the straight line on the back and middle lines, press the Delete button to delete it
Make the back and middle become a straight line
Select the back panel
Then select the rotation y-axis in the right-click menu
Then click the back and middle straight line to rotate the panel to the correct position
Now we will be in the panel section
Open the panel to create a seam line to make the clothing more suitable for the model
Select the seam tool and click on the level on the side of the waist to make the seam line the widest position
After pressing the mouse button, you can enter the specific number of the seam line
Set the width of the left and right sides to 10mm
View the seam line to ensure that it does not exceed the vertical position of the shoulder point on the inside side
And confirm to create a seam line
The seam line is actually a zero-shaped hole
The line on both sides will automatically create a seam line
Open the model, you will see that the shirt is more suitable than before
Switch to the back view to perform the same operation on the back
Check the wearing effect
Now the back seems to be not tight enough
You can tighten it a little more
Use the adjustment panel tool to select a seam line
The point that drags the seam line on both sides will be widened
If you directly increase the width, the center position of the seam line will be changed along with it
Therefore, we need to use the center point function
Double-click the center point of the seam line
The center point that changes color with the point is activated
At this time, when we drag the point of the seam line to modify the shape
Use the center point position as a fixed center to modify
After simulation, after confirming the effect is appropriate
We will add a long shirt
Make it into a skirt
Use the edit panel tool to select all the seam lines
Then drag these lines
While dragging, press the Shift key
You can move them along the vertical direction
When dragging the seam line
Double-click to enter the specific vertical
Open the simulation, you will find that the skirt is a little tight near the buttocks
Move the point on the side of the skirt
Make the lower part of the skirt wider
When moving the point
Press the Shift key
You can open the reference line and level it
When moving, press the Shift key to enter the specific vertical
Move the bottom and side points of the front and back slices to the outside 40 mm
To modify the application
Now that the size of the clothes is appropriate
We will adjust the throat part
Make it more natural
The upper and lower ends of this throat are a bit out of place
Like poking out
We can move the bottom point of the throat down a little
To make the part of the throat that was dug out more naturally
Do the same on the back
Now we will turn the throat into a part of the cut line
Use the internal multilinear line tool
From the upper and lower ends of the throat
To draw the internal line on the outside of the cut line
Press the Ctrl key and click
You can create a curve point
In order to turn the internal line into a curve
Double click to complete the creation
Then on the back of the 3D window
Click on the position near the internal line as a reference
Go to the blue reference point
Start drawing the starting point
Then connect to the end point of the throat
Then complete the creation of the rest of the internal line
Use the editor tool to select the internal line
Then select the cut and sew
Press the Shift key
Select the two internal lines connecting the throat
Then select the cut and sew
The plate will be cut into two separate plates
After opening the simulation
You will find that the cut position is not very smooth
Let's adjust the depth of the throat
To make the angle more natural
Move this point of the throat to both sides
To make the angle a little bit flatter
Do the same for the other point of the throat
When the clothing effect is suitable
We use the deepening round-shape curve tool
To turn the excess corner into a round corner
To turn the excess corner into a round-shape curve
When you switch to the deepening round-shape curve tool
Click on the
It turns it into a round corner
This makes the超id bang a nothing
Similarly you can find the longerória point
It can be made on the bottom of a support
In addition, there is a punch anytime
In addition, there is an and
There are some bumps near the support point
We can adjust it with the 만들 tool
you can adjust it with the ruler tool.
Set the shrink rate to 1%
to slightly shrink the position of the brush brush.
Click on the part of the brush brush to brush the shrink effect,
then simulate to check the effect.
Now it's flat.
Rotate the view to see if there are other places that need to be adjusted.
Set the brush brush size to be smaller
to take the shrink position more accurately.
The throat on the back is also operated in the same way.
Reduce the surface diameter of the virtual model a little.
Modify to change the application.
Now the front, middle and bottom are not flat.
Let's modify the sewing line.
Use the editor sewing line tool
to move the end point of the sewing line to the end point of the line.
After the simulation,
you will see that the bottom of the door is changed
to a flat line.
Change to the editor sewing line tool
We will adjust the sewing line.
Delete the straight line point
and turn the whole bottom into a whole horizontal line.
Drag the bottom down a little
You will find that the side line is curved.
In order to keep the side as a straight line,
we need to delete the curve point.
After selecting the weight,
select the single selection of the line and delete all the curve points.
Change the sleeve to be longer.
Now the sleeve is a little too wide.
We need to adjust it.
We will use the extension tool
to keep the seam line unchanged.
Make the sleeve narrower.
Click on the highest point of the sleeve
to start creating an extension line.
Press the Shift key to create an extension line in the vertical direction.
Click to complete the creation of the extension line.
After creating the extension line,
the extension line can be modified on both sides at the same time.
Move the mouse to open the effect.
Please make sure that this version is narrower.
Click on the app to modify.
Now you will see that the sleeve line is unchanged.
It's just similar to a rotation.
To simulate and observe the sleeve hole,
you will find that the sleeve is narrower.
Next, we are going to make the bubble sleeve effect.
We still need to use the extension tool.
But this time we are going to come back to create an extension line.
Start from the bottom
and create an extension line at the highest point of the sleeve.
Click on the extension line to open the top of the sleeve on both sides at the same time.
Click on the right position to confirm the extension.
Then you will see that we need to adjust the seam line.
We need to connect the pleats to the top of the sleeve.
Use the edit seam line tool to select the seam line on the sleeve.
Press the delete button to delete them.
Use the free sewing tool to create an extension line 1 to 1 along the sleeve.
Click on the 3D window to confirm that we want to center the pleats.
Then, based on the blue reference point just now,
create the first extension line in the sleeve of the large body version.
Then select the other extension line on the sleeve.
The back is also the same operation.
Next, we are going to create an extension line 1 to n between the top of the sleeve and the remaining part of the sleeve.
Select the extension line on the sleeve of a whole section first,
then press the Shift button.
Follow the direction of the extension, select the two lines of the large body,
then release the Shift button.
Open the model and apply the edit.
Then, adjust the position of the extension line 1 to 2.
Reduce the ratio of the pleats to 10 to achieve a more detailed effect.
Turn the straight line point into a curve point, then press the X key to switch to the plus point division tool to create a new
If you want a more obvious bulge effect, you can pull the embroidery point up a little more
If you feel that the bubble sewing effect is not obvious enough, you can continue to repeat the previous steps and use the extension tool to open the top to make the top more fabric
Since we have used the extension tool again, we need to adjust the sewing line
First, move the free sewing line end point of the 1 to 1 section to the equal position
Then follow the sewing line end point of the pleats part
The other side of the sleeve is also the same operation
When you open the model, you will see that the bubble sewing effect has become very obvious
Now we will modify the sleeve mouth part
Now the middle part of the sleeve is too short, we delete the straight line point caused by the extension
Now the middle part of the sleeve is a little longer, we need to adjust it a little
First, we need to know that in order to make the sleeve connect more smoothly to the seam side, we need to make sure that the bottom is straight
So we need to use the extension tool to drag the bottom of the sleeve line and turn it into a circle, so that both sides are straight
Now you can see in the 3D window that the seam line is very flat, and then we will start to roll up the sleeve
Use the extension tool to select the bottom line of the sleeve, and create a folding line using the internal sewing line function
Enter the sewing line 20, then click OK
Then select the folding arrangement tool, select the internal sewing line, then use the positioning ball to fold the sleeve
Drag the shaft on the positioning ball and fold the bottom up
The printed sleeve makes them fold more clearly and more stable
When the sleeve is folded, cancel their printing
Now we will continue to add the skirt
In order to prevent the insertion problem after inserting the skirt, we now need to temporarily turn the shirt skirt into a tight state
Select all large-body panels, adjust the tail shrink rate to 60, then turn on the simulation
Now the panels are shrinked on the tail, making the shirt skirt look like a tight skirt
Reduce the conflict thickness of all panels to 1 to get a more intimate effect
Next, add the Nurse Outfit file we shared with you to the work area window
Select Add as Download
After inserting, move the panels to a position that does not overlap with other panels
The cold inner panels will have conflicts with other panels while maintaining the current form
Open the simulation, after the simulation is stable, we can adjust the length of the skirt
Use the edit panel tool to move the bottom panel to the appropriate position
Then activate the shirt skirt and combine them to simulate
Return the tail shrink rate of the shirt skirt to the original value, then simulate again
If it is not stable, please increase the tail shrink rate to 80%, then 90%, and finally 100%
Now we will start making the nurse hat
Add the Nurse Hat file we provided to the work area
Use the fold arrangement tool to fold the hat along the inner line position
Then move the folded panel to the head area
When the panel is close to the virtual model head, press the W key to add a pin on the panel and fix it in 3D space
Then print the panel to make the fold more intense
Activate simulation
Now the panel has fallen to the head, we will use the pin to fold the back of the nurse hat
Press the W key to click on the two corners of the panel to add a pin
Then open the simulation, move the pin to fold the back of the hat
Try to get these two corners as close to the head as possible
Please make sure that one corner is very flat on the other corner
Then press the W key to click on the pin to delete them
Then create a sewing line between these two internal lines
Please check the 3D window to confirm that the sewing line direction is matching
Add a pin to the corner at the bottom to fix this corner, then start to simulate
After opening the simulation, move the pin to continue it close to the model head
Then reduce the粒子間距到10,衝突厚度降低到1並模擬一下
Then use the folding arrangement tool to fold down the top panel of the hat
And drag the panel to keep it straight
Change the movement tool to select the On key, then delete the pin
Turn the pin to the back and place it close to the panel of the head
And then select to fix it to the virtual model
The last pin is fixed to the virtual model
Then when you simulate
you will find that the hat is already fixed on the virtual model's head.
Now the hat will not fall off easily.
Use the same method to fix it to the side of the nurse hat.
When you fix the pin to the virtual model,
it will automatically fix it to the recent virtual model grid peak.
Using this method can help us make the hat more suitable for the virtual model.
Open the simulation, drag the hat board and adjust the balance of the hat.
Then remove the hardening of the board.
Check the physical properties of the fabric used for the hat.
You will find that the curve of this hat is very high.
This is because we can still see that it is harder after hardening,
which supports the whole hat.
Now let's adjust the physical properties of the skirt.
Unlock the shirt skirt.
Replace the thick texture surface.
Select all the sheets that form the shirt skirt.
Click on the application of the fabric window to apply a new fabric for them.
Then go to the property editor.
Select a pre-set fabric for this fabric.
Here I choose cotton tulle.
This is a fabric suitable for working clothes and sweaters.
Open the simulation.
You will see that because this fabric is not easy to stretch,
the creases are easier to produce and become more obvious.
Then use the editor tool to select the sewing line.
Open the sewing line in the property editor.
Since this side is stacked with an easy-to-stretch sewing line,
the creases on the other side will be more obvious.
You will see theื
Then open the ease called the продолжating sewing line.
Next we unlock the skirt and iron all the clothes together.
Here there are 3 places where you can unlock the skirt.
You can match them according to the rolling board.
Here they are one and the same.
Then we can unlock both feet.
Here are 3 places where you can unlock the skirt and iron.
Here are 3 places where you can unlock both feet.
You can also reduce the conflict thickness and the strength of the particles.
After the simulation is complete, delete the excess collar fold line and simulate again.
Next, we can reduce the particle diameter of the shirt skirt to 5 to get more detailed clothing details.
Then delete the fold line on the sleeve and simulate to get a more natural fold effect.
That's it for this tutorial.
If you have any questions, feel free to comment or message us.
Thank you for your support. See you next time.